土耳其共和国法律
LAWS OF REPUBLIC OF TURKEY
可怜的阿加
Poor Agah.
穆尼尔?
Munir?
你在哪里？
Where are you, my boy?
穆尼尔?
Munir?
快出来，该吃早餐了
Come on boy, it's time for breakfast.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
穆尼尔?
Munir!
你在哪？
Where are you, sir?
穆尼尔?
Munir?
您去度假了吗？
Have you gone to a vacation or something?
没有
No.
穆尼尔从来没有独自在家待过吗？
So Munir has never been alone?
没有
No.
您从来没有忘记给它喂食吗？
You haven't delayed his treatment?
没有，我给它的食物是您给我用于治疗它的......
No, I was giving him the cat food that you gave me for his...
急性肾功能衰竭
Acute kidney failure.
是的
Yes.
他是因此而死吗？
Did he die because of that?
因为急性肾衰竭
Because of acute kidney failure.
不仅如此，它已经脱水了
Not just that. The cat has also been dehydrated.
什么？
How?
穆尼尔 - 我可爱的猫
MUNIR - MY LOVELY CAT
兄弟，我们该拿她怎么办？
Man, what are we going to do with her?
她来这里已经六个月了
She's been here for six months.
但人们仍然在谈论内芙拉
and they are still talking about Nevra.
你是因为睡不到她才觉得难受吧
You are bothered because you couldn't sleep with her.
滚蛋，你他妈在说什么？
Fuck off. What the fuck are you talking about?
我有很多同学想来这里都想疯了
How many of my classmates is crazy about coming here
你知道吗？
do you know?
她简直就是凭空出现的
She literally came here out of nowhere.
你知道为什么吗？因为她是女人
Do you know why? Because she is a woman.
他们称之为积极性区别对待
They called it positive discrimination.
哪里有积极的一面？
What part of this is positive?
外面有好多猛男呢
There are many strong men out there.
但对他们来说，有必要将内芙拉放在首位
But for them it's necessary to put Nevra into the spotlight.
内芙拉 内芙拉
Nevra, Nevra.
去他妈的“人力资源部”
Fuck that thing called 'human resources'.
这和这有什么关系？
What does it have to do with that?
假设您和内芙拉在一起执勤
Let's say you're out there with Nevra.
你会信任内芙拉吗？你会信任她吗？
Would you trust Nevra? Could you trust her?
如果是个拿枪的男人，我会相信的
I would trust more if it was a man holding the gun.
至少很清楚他会做什么
At least it would be clear what he'd do.
是啊
See
她应该滚出这个地方了
She can get the fuck out of here.
但是绝不能让她轻易离开
But she shouldn't go without a fuck.
必须的
Definitely.
奴尔滕，你能安排下星期的预约吗？
Nurten, could you schedule an appointment for next week, please?
阿加 贝尤鲁
Agah Beyoglu.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了
Now...
首先我们应该通知您的家人
First thing we should do is to inform your family.
他们必须先知道这件事
They have to know about this first.
你老婆已经去世了
Your wife had passed away.
是的
Yes.
已经十年了
It's been 10 years.
你有一个女儿
You have a daughter.
是的，但是她不在这里，她住在国外
Yes, but she's not here, she's living abroad.
没关系，你应该通知她
Doesn't matter, you should inform her.
她可以打电话给我，我想和她聊一下
She may even call me, I would like to talk to her.
明白了吗？
Are we clear?
明白
Yes.
祝你好胃口
Bon appetit.
我在想是否应该重做检测，以防结果不准确
I was thinking if we should redo the test, in case the results are wrong.
我认识一个叫内奇米的人
I knew a guy named Necmi.
-他们说他得了癌症，但是后来......-我知道
- They said he had cancer but then... - I know.
我知道
I know.
很难接受
It's hard to accept.
但是结果很清楚
But the results are clear.
症状也是如此
So are the symptoms.
诊断毫无疑问，阿加
For me, there is no doubt in this diagnosis, Agah.
你有早期的老年痴呆症
You have early stage Alzheimer's.
爸爸
Yes, Dad?
宝贝
Honey.
爸爸，我做不下去了，我已经忍无可忍了
Dad, I can't do it. I can't bear this anymore.
怎么了？我打电话给总检察长
What happened? I'll call the Chief Inspector
爸爸，我不是孩子了，我不需要你打电话给任何人
Dad, I'm not a kid. I don't want you to call anyone.
那你为什么给我打电话
Then why did you call me?
闺女？
Daughter?
闺......
Dau...
但是医生，我记得所有事情
But doctor, I remember everything.
人们患老年痴呆症时会忘记事情
People forget things when they have Alzheimer's.
我在法院工作了27年
I worked at the courthouse for 27 years.
如果我现在过去，我还记得所有文件的位置
If I went there now I'd remember where every file is.
你还处于初期
You are in the early stages.
随便问我生日，朋友的电话号码等等……
Ask me then, anything. My anniversary, friends' phone numbers...
这些我都记得很熟
I know them by heart.
我的朋友曾经说我就像电话簿
My friends used to call me I was like a phone book.
当年我们无法保存电话号码，所以我就记在脑子里
Back then we couldn't save the numbers so I memorized them.
阿加
Agah.
你忘记给猫喝水了
You forgot to give water to your cat.
你忘了给它喂食
You forgot to feed him.
它饿死了
He starved to death.
我怎么会这样？怎么回事？
How could I do that? How?
可怜的穆尼尔
Poor Munir.
听好，这是早期诊断
Look, this is an early diagnosis.
对治疗有极大的帮助
This will be of tremendous help for the treatment.
我们有一些患者在确诊后已经生活了20年
We have patients that lived 20 years after the diagnosis.
所以请放心
So rest assured.
活了20年，但他们还记得自己的生活吗？
Lived 20 years but do they remember what they lived?
老年痴呆症直接影响记忆
Alzheimer's directly affects memory.
这是痴呆症的主要原因之一
It's one of the main reasons for dementia.
但是，我们将竭尽所能保持您的头脑活跃
But we will do all we can to stall this and to keep your mind alive.
但是迟早我会忘记的，对吗？
But sooner or later, I will forget things, right?
现在先不要考虑这些
Don't think about this now.
我所有的记忆，经历都将被抹去
All my memories, experiences will be erased, they will go away.
然后我会怎样？
What will happen to me?
我是说……
I mean...
电话号码没有多重要
Phone numbers aren't that important.
但是我的人格将会怎样？
But what will happen to my personality?
也会被抹掉吗？
Wouldn't it be erased too?
我会忘记我是什么样的人
I will forget what kind of man I am.
你还活着，但你并不存在
You are alive but you don't exist.
怎么会有人忍受得了呢？
How can someone endure this?
您可以把它放在口袋里
You may put this in your pocket.
我来检查一下声音，请说点什么
I'll check the sound, say something, please.
我应该说什么？
What should I say? Hi.
您可以数一下星期几
You can count the days of the week.
星期五，星期六，星期天
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
星期一
Monday.
星期二，星期三
Tuesday, Wednesday.
星期四，星期五
Thursday, Friday.
可以了
That should do.
让我们开始吧
Let's get started.
我从一个基本问题开始
I'll start with a basic question.
在拥有140名员工的凶杀科中
How does it feel to be the only woman
作为唯一的女性，您感觉如何？
working in an homicide bureau with 140 staff members?
感觉怎么样？
How does it feel?
当然很棒
Of course it's amazing.
我感到非常荣幸
I feel very privileged.
首先，我们所有人都是凶杀科的成员
First of all, all of us here are part of the homicide bureau.
这里几乎没有任何性别歧视
It's impossible to see anything like gender discrimination
或其他任何歧视的行为
or any other sexist approaches in this institution.
没有任何问题，我的朋友们都很支持我
Instead of any problems, my friends are supporting me so much.
对我来说也是一种责任
Which also means another responsibility for me.
我正在尽我所能来得到他们的支持
I am trying to do my best to be worthy of their support.
您的专业是公共管理，对吗？
You studied public administration, right?
是
Yes.
您还在私营企业做过经理
You even worked as a manager in private sector
但后来您决定报名参加警察学院
but then you decided to enroll at the police academy.
是
Yes.
您为什么决定当警察？
Why did you decide to become a police officer?
我一直都想做，因为……
I always thought about it because...
我的父亲是一名警察，他是我生命中最伟大的人
The greatest man I know was a policeman... My father.
现在退休了
Who is currently retired.
随着成长，我开始理解一些事情
You start to understand things as you grow.
我们几乎看不到我们父亲
We barely saw our father.
也许周末可以，但只有一天
Maybe at the weekends, just for a day.
我曾经很讨厌他
I used to resent him.
我曾经说他更关心别人
I used to tell him that he cares about other people more.
看来我父亲的工作就是关心别人
It seems that my father's job is to care about other people.
他把这个概念深深地印在我的脑海里
And he ingrained this concept in me so much
以至于我不知道如何以其他方式生活
that I don't know how to live any other way.
我在每次访谈时都会重复这句话
I actually repeat this in every interview
但是当警察对我来说从来就不是一份工作
but being a police officer is not a job for me, never has been.
有一个概念叫做善良
There is a concept called goodness.
对我来说，成为一名警察意味着成为善良的一部分
For me, being a police officer means being a part of that goodness.
那就是我的目标
That's my purpose...
做一个好人
To become a good person...
德瓦!
Deva!
德瓦，回答我！昨晚你在哪里过夜？
Deva, answer me! Where were you last night?
德瓦，回答我！
Deva, answer me!
喂？
Yes?
祖哈尔，你好亲爱的
Zuhal, hello my dear.
等一下
Wait a minute.
告诉我昨晚你在哪里
Tell me where were you last night.
看着我！
Look at me!
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
那你跟我来啊
Come with me then.
你不可以出去！
You're not going!
德瓦，我要揍死你!
Deva, I'll fuck you up!
德瓦!
Deva!
喂？
Yes?
亲爱的，这个时间不方便吗？我吵醒你了吗？现在几点了？
My dear, is this a bad time? Did I wake you up? What time is it there?
不，我们都醒着，这边是早上，出什么事情了？
No, we are awake. It's morning here. Is something wrong?
我给我的女儿打电话还需要理由吗？
Do I need a reason to call my daughter?
我都不记得你上一次来电话是什么时候了
I don't remember the last time you called.
一直都是我给你打电话
I'm the one who always calls.
德瓦怎么样？
How is Deva?
德瓦快把我逼疯了
Deva is making me crazy!
德瓦不听我的话，我们甚至不能沟通……
Deva doesn't listen to me, we can't even talk...
爸爸，你吃了我寄给你的维生素吗？
Dad, did you take the vitamins I sent you?
吃了，谢谢
I did, thank you.
但是不可以吃太多，可能会导致糖尿病
But don't take them in high doses, they may cause diabetes.
每天吃一片
You take one.
持续服用三个月
And keep taking for three months...
服用三个月，然后停用一个月
Take them for three months then stop taking for a month.
然后你再服用三个月，别忘了
Then you take them for another three months. Don't ignore it.
你也不听话
You didn't listen either.
什么？
What?
你小时候也不听我们的
You didn't listen to us when you were young either.
是吗？
Is that so?
你怎么知道的？
How would you know?
你怎么知道的？德瓦今年16岁
How would you know? Deva is 16 years old.
我16岁那年是我在寄宿学校的第5年
When I was 16, it was my fifth year on boarding school.
还记得你把我送走了吗？
Remember that you sent me away?
你和我在一起吗？
Were you with me?
妈妈和我在一起吗？
Was my mother there?
你怎么知道我听话不听话？
How would you know if I had listened someone or not?
你知道我在做什么吗？
Did you know what I was doing?
你知道我现在在做什么吗？
Do you know what I'm doing right now? No!
我能怎么办，亲爱的，你逃到了世界的另一端，去了澳大利亚
What can I do, my dear. You ran away to the other side of the world, to Australia.
爸，我要离婚了
Dad, I'm getting a divorce.
你有什么想说的吗？
Do you have any idea about this?
爸，对不起
Dad, I'm sorry.
我不是故意的，我很难过
I didn't mean to. I am very upset.
对不起，请原谅我
I'm sorry, please forgive me.
你刚才要说什么？刚才……
Were you going to say something? Were you...
我们来为内芙拉干杯
I propose a toast for Nevra.
每周都有不同的采访
Different interviews, every week.
我们之中总算出了个名人
Finally, one of us is famous.
别傻了，我可不是什么名人
Don't be silly, I'm not famous.
等等，这是什么？
Oh, wait, what was it?
敬内芙拉……
To Nevra...
让朋友安心，让敌人敬畏
Who reassures friends and awes foes.
敬内芙拉宝宝！
To Nevra the po-po!
-你说啥？-她说宝宝
- What do you mean by po-po? - She said po-po.
总是在电影里看到，我一直想说
They say that in the movies all the time. I've always wanted to say po-po.
很好，你们说完了吗，我可以现在喝吗？
Nice, are you finished? May I drink now?
撇开玩笑不提，内芙拉，你为什么去当警察？
All jokes aside, Nevra, why did you become a police officer?
什么意思？
What do you mean 'why'?
这是一个简单的问题
It's a simple question.
你为什么要成为法西斯主义者？
Why did you become a fascist?
你在说什么？犯什么傻？
What are you saying? Are you a troll?
喝醉了吗？
Are you drunk?
等一下，我很好奇
Hang on, I am curious.
我们很少聚在一起，你别这样说话
We meet very rarely and you say these things.
你其实是在问我
You are actually asking me this...
为什么我没有进入保险公司？
Why didn't I get into an insurance company?
为什么我没有去财政部？
Why I am not in the ministry of finance?
为什么我没有做银行家？
Why I am not a banker?
为什么我不像大学里的革命主义者那样嫁给有钱人
Why I didn't act like a revolutionist in college and then marry a rich guy
像你一样没事做混日子？
and sit on my ass all day without working, like you?
这是我的答案
Here is my answer...
我不想这样
I didn't want to.
我想……
I wanted to do...
我想做些事
I wanted to do something...
有意义的事
Something real.
做什么？
What is that?
这是一个简单的问题
It's a simple question.
你为什么成为法西斯主义者？
Why did you become a fascist?
我只是在开玩笑
I'm just kidding.
她生气了
She's offended.
她上学时也是这样
She was like that in college too.
来吧
Come on.
敬这么多年后的重聚
To reuniting after all these years.
敬这个美丽的夜晚
To this beautiful night.
蒙塔兹!
Mumtaz!
阿加，我在这里
Agah, I'm here...
-这边，阿加-借过
- Come, Agah. Come here. - Excuse me.
这就是为什么我愿意不来这里
That's why I don't come here.
人群，醉汉，喧闹声……
The crowd, the drunks, the noise...
我公寓里的流浪汉就够多了
Bums in my apartment are enough for me
你还带我来这里
and you brought me here.
你已经习惯了
You are used to this Agah.
没有，我还是不习惯
I'm not. I couldn't get used to them.
你在这里住了多久了？
How long have you lived here?
如果你不想住在这里，就卖掉您的公寓
If you don't want to live here, sell your apartments
离开这里
and move away.
我才不走！
I won't go!
我是姓贝尤鲁的，要走也是他们走
My last name is Beyoglu, they'll go.
-你会的-我不会
- You will. - I won't.
-你会走的！-我才不走
- You will brother! - I won't go away.
绝不
I won't.
很久没见到你了，阿加
It's been so long since I saw you, Agah.
如果我没有给你打电话，我们可能永远都不会见面
If I hadn't called you, we were never going to meet.
怎么了，你的生活中是否有你爱的人？
What's wrong man? Is there someone in your life?
你在和谁约会吗？还是在忽略我们？
Are you dating someone? Are you ignoring us?
我没有忽略，我只是没有时间
I'm not ignoring, I just don't have time.
滚蛋，我们都这把年纪，只剩下时间了
Fuck off. In our age, time is all we have.
你真是可笑
You are a joke.
别这么内向
Don't become introverted.
我早上可以带你去博斯普鲁斯海峡
I can come and take you to Bosphorus in mornings.
过来
Come here.
-怎么了，先生 -尝尝这个
- Yes, sir. - Taste this.
-味道不好吗 -尝一尝
- Does it taste bad? - Just taste it.
我可以告诉厨师为您重做一份
I can tell the cook to prepare another for you.
为什么？
Why?
您不喜欢
You didn't like it.
我没要你另外准备，我是说让你尝一尝
I didn't say that. I said 'taste this'.
你为什么要找他麻烦？
Why are you bothering him?
他另外准备新的给你
He's offering a new one.
那不是重点，人们不互相倾听
That's not the point. People don't listen to each other.
也许味道不错，我不明白
Maybe it tastes good and I don't get it.
回去上班吧，去吧
Just go back to work. Come on.
-走吧 -不用
- Go. - No!
你真让我吃惊
You surprised me.
我们平静，温柔的阿加
Our peaceful, sweet Agah
骂了服务员，我真不敢相信
scolding the waiter. I can't believe it.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
人们都不能认真的倾听对方
People don't listen to each other properly.
自动应答，无需等待
Automatic answers without waiting.
现在一切都自动化了，他们竟然说我们无法相处
Everything is automated now, and they say we can't get along.
别生气了
Don't get mad, okay.
我们吃完就走吧，我们去别的地方
Let's eat and go, we'll go somewhere else.
我不该来，太晚了
I shouldn't come, it's late.
那是自动答案，一点都不晚，现在是晚上8:30
That's the automatic answer. It's not late, it's 8:30 pm.
穆阿兹还想见你呢
Muazzez also asked to see you.
她叫我带你过去
She told me to bring you with me.
我们的朋友组织了一个活动，我们应该……
Our friends organized an event that we should...
什么活动？
Where did that event come out from?
看在上帝的份上！我们一起去
For god's sake! We're going.
就这样，我的前列腺毁了我
That's it. My prostate destroyed me.
毁了我，使我痛苦
Destroyed me, made me miserable.
带我来这里干嘛？
What am I doing here?
等等，我给你介绍一个人
Just hang on, I'll introduce you to someone.
这就是你把我带到这里的原因？
So is that why you brought me here?
这是个什么陷阱吗？
Did you set a trap for me?
那是努赫特，这是我曾跟你提过的朋友，阿加
That's Nukhet. And this is my friend I told you about, Agah.
努赫特
Nukhet.
你好，很高兴见到你
Hi, nice to meet you.
你好
Hello.
努赫特一直在上探戈课
Nukhet has been taking tango lessons
我告诉她你是一位探戈大师
and I told her that there is a tango master here.
得了吧
Come on...
您不会介意指点努赫特跳舞吧？
You wouldn't mind teaching Nukhet a thing or two, right?
这是我的荣幸
It would be my pleasure.
所以他们跳得很好，不是吗？
So... They're doing a great job, aren't they?
是的，但是跟我们有什么关系吗？
Yeah but, what's with us?
你又懵了，为什么不去喝点什么呢？
You are confused again, why don't you drink something?
不，我不想像他们一样
No, I don't want to. I don't want to be like them.
他们很快就会喝醉了
They will be drunk soon.
他们会让自己难堪
They will embarrass themselves.
当他们醒来时会后悔的
And they will regret everything when they wake up.
他们为什么会后悔？
Why would they regret?
他们喝醉了
They'll just get drunk.
不会记住任何事情
They won't remember anything in the morning.
真好
How nice.
既然我会忘记
Since I won't remember
我就可以做任何我想做的事，是吗？
I can do anything I want, is that so?
正是
Exactly.
真好啊
How nice.
我会统统忘掉，所以我可以做任何事情
I won't remember, so I can do anything.
但是早上还是会醒来的，不是吗？
Won't they wake up in the morning?
你又在纠结这个了，阿加
You're obsessed with this again, Agah.
蒙塔兹
Mumtaz!
伤心欲绝
Eat one's heart out...
有趣的句子
Interesting sentence.
那是良心
That's conscience.
从字面上看，它可以吞噬您的心
It can eat your heart out, literally.
永远忘记
Forgetting forever.
忘记你正在忘记
Forgetting that you are forgetting.
对，就是这样
Yes, that's it.
我会忘记一切
I will forget everything.
我会统统忘掉
I won't remember anything.
敬阿加
To Agah.
我不会忘记
I'm not forgetting.
再来一杯
One more please.
阿加!
Agah!
你要走了吗？
Are you leaving?
我有点急事
I had an emergency.
你随时可以打电话给我
You can call me whenever you want.
很高兴认识你
I am very glad to meet you.
我也是
So am I.
祝你有一个美好的夜晚
Have a good night.
阿迪坎法院物证室
ARDICHAN COURTHOUSE PROPERTY AND EVIDENCE UNIT
没有强奸
There was no rape.
我谋杀罪我认，但绝对没有强奸
I accept the murder but there was no rape.
审讯相机
INTERROGATION CAMERA
她不是鱼塘里唯一的一条鱼
She is not the only fish in the sea.
-女孩们都很喜欢我 -是吗？
- All the girls love me. - Is that so?
-我一个眼神她们就都融化了 -真的吗？
- They melt with my one look. - Really?
例如那个女人
For example, that woman.
哪个女人
Which woman?
那个女警察
That police woman.
-她在追我-是吗？
- She was running after me... - Is that so?
告诉我停下来
Told me to stop.
她掏出枪，我就停下来
She pulled her gun and I stopped.
然后我转身看着她
Then I turned and looked at her.
-你知道发生了什么吗？-什么？
- Do you know what happened? - What?
-她看起来已经爱上我了-真的吗？
- She looked like she literally melted. - Really?
伙计们
So, guys...
托尔加·亚兹甘首席检验员
TOLGA YAZGAN CHIEF INSPECTOR
这件事到此为止
This incident stays in this room.
-清楚吗？-清楚，长官
- Is that clear? - It is clear, Chief.
菲鲁兹?
Firuz?
什么？
What?
是的，长官
Yeah, it is Chief.
伙计们
Guys...
还以为我不知道你们排挤内芙拉的事吗？
Do you think I don't know about your messing with Nevra?
从现在起，不准任何人招惹内芙拉
No one will mess with Nevra from now on!
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
你将调到行政部门做文书工作
And you will be working on documentation in administration.
不再执行外勤任务
No more field duties.
还愣着干什么？
Guys, we are done. Why are you still here?
出去
Go.
警察证书
CERTIFICATE
不负责任——汤姆·琼斯
"Not Responsible" by Tom Jones.
犯罪记录
CRIMINAL RECORDS
你女儿还没打电话给我
Your daughter hasn't called yet.
她很忙，但我已经告诉她了
She's very busy, but I told her.
她怎么说？
What did she say?
-她很快就会来的-不错
- She'll come here soon. - Nice.
吃药了吗？
Are you taking your medicines?
-是的 -很好
- Yes. - Nice.
好的
Okay.
最近
Recently...
上个星期
Last week...
你无缘无故生气了吗？
Have you gotten angry for no reason?
发脾气之类的
Something like a tantrum.
-没有-不错
- Not really. - Nice.
我问这个是因为您随时都可能发脾气
I'm asking this because this tantrum may occur any time.
您可能会感到不安全
You may feel insecure.
您可能对以前没有在意过的事情很敏感
You may be sensitive about something that you haven't cared about before.
这些事情都有可能发生
These things may happen.
如果发生了类似的情况，记下来
If something like this happens, take a note.
您开始做功课了吗？
Have you started doing your homework?
您开始记笔记了吗？
Have you started taking notes?
我的名字叫阿加 贝尤鲁I，我把我的电视机扔到街上
MY NAMES IS AGAH BEYOGLU. I THREW MY TV INTO THE STREET.
-我有做笔记-非常好
- I'm taking notes, yes. - Very good.
好，体育锻炼呢？
Okay, what about physical activities?
你要多走路
You were going to walk.
你应该努力，做简单的运动也可以
You should make an effort, I said simple sports may also do.
是的，我有锻炼身体
Yes, I am doing those things.
-我现在很活跃-非常好
- I'm very active nowadays. - Very good.
好吧，让我们谈谈心理活动
Okay, let's talk about mental activities.
我们应该激活那些从未起作用的大脑神经元
We should activate your brain neurons that have never worked until now.
要怎么做？
How will we do that?
例如
For example...
我的一位患者熟悉拉丁语言
One of my patients was familiar with Latin languages.
后来开始学习日语
And she started learning Japanese.
并从中受益匪浅
And she benefited a lot from it.
你要我学日语吗？
You want me to learn Japanese?
不是的
No.
每个人都有不同的兴趣
Everyone has a different interest.
一定有您一直想做但做不到的事情
There must be something that you always wanted to do but you couldn't.
我有很多想做的事
There are many things I want to do.
就是这样，很好
That's it, very good.
不管是什么事，要如何做
Look, whatever it is, however it is done...
开始做计划吧
You will start doing it with utmost planning.
计划就是关键词
Look, planning is the key word here.
您应该有每日，每周，每月的计划
You should have daily, weekly, monthly plans.
并且应该检查是否按照计划执行
You should check if you are following those plans accordingly.
不要走任何捷径
You won't cut corners.
让这件事变得复杂
You'll make it complicated.
做好细节
You'll detail it.
假设您要给植物浇水
Let's assume that you'll water a plant.
要把植物的每一片叶子都喷水
You'll spray every leaf of that plant
一片接一片，耐心地做
one by one, patiently.
你会很享受你正在做的事情
You should enjoy what you're doing.
阿加，这样你会做到完美
Agah, you'll do that in such an impeccable way
这颗植物根本无法判断是在下雨还是在浇水
that the plant won't be able to tell if it's raining or you're watering it.
明白吗？
Are we clear?
-我很清楚 -很好
- We are clear. - Nice.
非常好
Very nice.
好，跟我说说
Okay, now tell me...
您最近感觉如何？
How have you been feeling lately?
从来没有这么好过
I've never felt so good.
安全检查
SECURITY CLEARANCE
身份证副本
IDENTIFICATION CARD COPY
谁啊？
Damn it.
-什么事？-你是修理工，所以你应该知道
- What? - You are a mechanic, so you should know.
为什么修理工总是迟到？
Why are mechanics always late?
什么？
What?
例如我们的电梯修理工，我们等了很久，但他没来
Our elevator mechanic for instance, we waited for so long but he didn't come.
过了很久他才来，但是他来得很晚
Then he came, but he was late.
你是谁，你在说什么？
Who are you, what are you saying?
我们要一辈子等修理工吗？
Are we going to wait for mechanics our whole lives?
-走开，这么晚了你到底要干嘛？-不，我要说的是
- Go away, it's so late... - No, I was going to say that...
你……你进来干什么？
You... Hey, what are you doing? Why are you going in?
很快就好
Just a sec...
把这些录入系统
You are going to write these down on computer.
也祝你早上好
Good morning to you too.
内政部
TO THE MINISTRY OF INTERIOR AFFAIRS
进来吧！
Come in!
这是什么？
What's this?
长官，这是我的辞职报告
My resignation, sir.
我不明白
Really, I didn't get it...
我知道是辞职信，我问你为什么
I can see that. I am asking why.
我必须辞职
I have to do that...
因为个人原因，请您批准
It's because of personal reasons. You'll put it in process.
我还没喝咖啡，还不清醒
I haven't had my coffee yet. I'm not awake yet.
你知道我会做什么吗？
Do you know what I'll do?
我把你的辞职报告
I'll take your resignation
放在我的抽屉里
and put it in my drawer.
给你五天假期
And I'll give you five days off.
回家休息一下，好好思考
Go home, get some rest, think this through
如果五天后你仍然想辞职，我会接受的
and if you still want to resign after five days, I'll accept it.
到时候我会批准，好吗？
I'll put your paper in process. Okay?
-但是，长官 -内芙拉！
- But, Chief... - Nevra!
你知道是我想让你进警察局的吗
Did you know that it was me who wanted you here at the bureau?
我从五十个女孩中选了你
I chose you from 50 girls.
不是因为你父亲是警察
It wasn't because your father was a cop.
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
因为在那50个人中，虽然你的工作前景光明
Because among those 50, it was only you determined to be
但只有你有决心做警察
a cop although you had a bright future in your job.
我告诉自己她疯了，而我恰好需要一个疯子在这里
I told myself that she was crazy and I needed someone crazy here.
回家好好想一想
Go home and think.
你好？
Yes?
声音小一点！
Turn it down!
她快把我逼疯了
She's driving me crazy.
她已经疯了，现在要让我疯了
She got crazy now she's making me crazy.
有什么事吗？
How can I help you?
我是阿加，阿加 贝尤鲁，来自法院
I'm Agah, Agah Beyoglu, from the courthouse.
-您是秘书处的 -是的
- From the secretary. - Yes.
已经好几年了……
It has been years...
我就觉得你看着很眼熟
I was thinking that you somehow look familiar.
我永远不会忘记我看到的每一张脸
I never forget a face that I saw.
-欢迎 -谢谢
- Welcome. - Thank you.
-进来 -谢谢
- Come, come in. - Thank you.
我们正在吃晚餐
We were just having dinner.
-饿了吗？我可以准备…… -不，谢谢
- Are you hungry? I can prepare for... - No, thank you.
对不起，有点乱
I'm sorry, it's a bit messy.
以前有一个女孩负责打扫房子，但是她把人家吓跑了
There was a girl cleaning the house but she ran away because of her.
每个人都被吓跑了
Everyone runs away.
谁能忍受这个？
Who would tolerate this?
你为什么不脱掉外套呢？
Why don't you take your coat off?
不用了，我感冒了
No thanks, I caught a cold.
-祝你快点好起来-谢谢
- Get well soon. - Thanks.
已经20年了，对吧？
It's been 20 years, right?
大概吧
I guess so.
你还记得阿加吗？
Do you remember Agah?
当我做档案工作的时候
When I was working on archives.
巡回法庭的塞拉尔推荐阿加，上帝保佑他
Celal from assize court recommended Agah, God bless him.
-他也过世了 -愿他安息
- He died too... - Really, may he rest in peace.
他每个周末去那里
He went there every weekend.
-是坎布拉吗？-是的，是坎布拉
- Was it Kambura? - Yes, it was Kambura.
阿加在坎布拉法院秘书处工作
Agah was working at the secretariat at Kambura Courthouse.
您帮我查了很多文件，对吗？
You opened many files for me right?
我们曾经一起去过那里
We went there with you once.
我们在河边吃鳟鱼，记得吗？
We ate trout near the river, remember?
-她已经这样四年了-她怎么了？
- She's been like this for four years. - What's wrong with her?
不好，阿加，很不好
It's bad, Agah, bad.
她得了老年痴呆症
She has Alzheimer's.
祝她快点好起来……
Get well soon.
她好不起来了
She won't get well.
看看她，她以前不是这样的
Look at her. She wasn't someone to be like this.
病魔已经毁了她
She's ruined.
她也毁了我们
She ruined us too.
我们的女儿住在马德里
Our daughter is living in Madrid.
我们去拜访她
We went to visit her.
我们在那里看了弗拉门戈表演
We watched a flamenco show there.
所有这些东西都是在那买的
All these things are from there.
怎么说呢……
How do they say...
费扎与生活的唯一联系就是这些
Feza's only connection to life is these.
我不知道为什么，她的记忆只保留了这些
I don't know why, her memory only kept these.
否则她既不认识我也不认识我们的女儿
Otherwise she neither knows me nor our girl.
来吧
Come on.
我要负责所有事情
I take care of everything.
我甚至要帮她擦屁股
I even clean her bottom.
就像我可以照顾自己似的
Like I can take care after myself.
对了，阿加
So, Agah.
-你退休了吗？-是的
- Are you retired? - Yes.
你老婆叫什么名字？
What was your wife's name?
梅布鲁雷
Mebrure.
她也去世了
She passed away too.
愿她安息
May she rest in peace.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿加，你来这里有什么事情吗？
So Agah, why did you come here?
怎么找到这个地方的？
How did you find this place?
我们认为这边的天气更好
We thought weather is better on this side.
离人群也很远
It's also far away from the crowds.
如果您不介意，我可以用一下洗手间吗？
May I use the bathroom if you don't mind?
我走了很长一段路
I've come a long way.
没问题
Yes, sure.
我也是这样
I have the same problem.
我的膀胱都凹陷了……
My bladder and all are sagged...
在那边
Look, it's over there.
喝一口吧
Come on, drink.
快喝！
Drink it woman!
-喝吧，来吧！-对不起
- Drink it, come on! - Excuse me.
你有远视眼镜吗？
Do you have farsighted glasses?
有，在那边
Yes, over there.
-在架子上-谢谢，我忘了带眼镜
- It's on the shelf. - Thanks, I forgot mine.
我已经忍无可忍了，只喝一口！
I'm running out of patience, just take one sip!
来吧，至少喝一小口
Come on, at least take one sip.
阿加，你在这附近做什么？
So Agah, what are you doing around here?
我有工作要做
I had work to do.
如果有什么我们能帮忙的尽管说
If there is something we can do, just say it. Don't be shy.
当然了
Yes, of course. I will.
我九岁的时候
I was nine years old.
那年是1961年
The year was 1961.
我妈妈为我的生日烤了一块蛋糕
My mom had baked a cake for my birthday.
那是第一次
That was the first time.
我许愿吹蜡烛
I made a wish blowing out candles.
我的愿望是这样的
My wish was this...
那时候
Back then
尤里·加加林将成为第一个进入太空的人
Yuri Gagarin was going to be the first man going to space.
我希望他能带我走
And I wished he would take me with him.
我非常相信我的愿望会成真，
I believed so much that my wish will come true
我准备了一个包，开始等待
I prepared a bag and started waiting.
我以为他们会从苏联大使馆来接我
I thought they will come from The Soviet Embassy to get me.
但是我听说他们是共产党员
But I was hearing that they were communists.
人们都说“小心，他们是共产党员”
People were saying "Careful, they are communists."
我说那我也要做共产党员
I said then I'll be one too.
那时候
During that time
一楼住了几个大学生
college students were staying on the first floor.
我妈妈也叫他们共产党员
My mom was calling them communists too
我知道他们在我家的地窖里藏了书
and I knew they had hidden books in our cellar.
我去那里偷了一本
I went there and stole one.
纳齐姆·希克梅特的诗歌集
Poems of Nazim Hikmet.
我记住了其中最短的一个
I found the shortest one and memorized it.
我以为如果俄国人来了，我给他们读这首诗
I thought if the Russians came, I'd read this poem to them
他们就会认为我是他们的一员，然后带我走
and they'd think I was one of them and take me.
长官？
Chief?
总之……
Anyways...
那天是4月12日
The date was April 12th.
航天飞机就要发射了
The space shuttle was going to be launched.
东方一号
Vostok-1.
但没人来接我
But no one had come for me.
我以为他们把我忘记了
I thought they forgot about me.
航天飞机发射了
The shuttle was launched.
每个人都在祈祷航天飞机穿过大气层
Everyone was praying for the shuttle to go through the atmosphere.
只有我在祈祷能中途停下，回来接我
Only I was praying for it to return half way around to take me.
也许还有美国人
And maybe the Americans
在祈祷沃斯托克不能进入太空
were praying for Vostok to not go into the space.
随便了
Whatever.
那一整天
All day long
在收音机旁边
near the radio
我默默地读那首诗
I read that poem silently.
我的头是泡沫状的云
My head is a foamy cloud.
我的内外都是大海
My inside and outside is a sea.
我是古尔哈内公园的一棵核桃树
I'm a walnut tree in Gulhane Park.
一棵老核桃树，长着树枝和碎片
An old walnut tree. With long branches and pieces.
你和警察都不知道这件事
Neither you are aware of this nor is the police.
我昨天遇到一个女孩，她的名字叫内芙拉·埃尔马斯
I MET A GIRL YESTERDAY. HER NAME WAS NEVRA ELMAS.
每当我读这首诗时，我都会觉得自己去了太空
Whenever I read this poem I feel like I go to space.
我今年65岁了
I am 65 years old now.
我像个孩子一样再次许愿
I made a wish again, just like a child.
当然是不可能实现的愿望
An impossible wish, of course.
你知道我想要什么吗？
Do you know what I wished for?
我想做个好人
To become a good person.
爸，我猜你在睡觉
Dad, I guess you are sleeping.
结束了，我不能再容忍这个人了，我们要搬回伊斯坦布尔
It's over, I can't tolerate this man no more. We are moving back to Istanbul.
我和德瓦一起回去
We are coming together with Deva.
我会再联系你
I'll call you later.
晚安
Good night.
凶杀局的第一位女警官
FIRST FEMALE POLICE OFFICER OF HOMICIDE BUREAU
她唯一的目标是做个好警察，做个好人
HER ONLY GOAL IS TO BE A GOOD POLICEMAN AND A GOOD PERSON